PENELOPE MAGAWAY

Digos City, Philippines · +63 961 000 1804 · +65 9641 3879 (WhatsApp) penelope_magaway@yahoo.com · penelopeCM.github.io

A Google data analytics professional committed to pursuing a long-term career change as a data analyst. Good understanding and proficiency of platforms for effective data analyses, including SQL, Sheets, Excel, and Tableau. Offers a 10+ year track record demonstrating strong analytical and problem-solving skills, computer proficiency and ability to follow through with projects from inception to completion.

SKILLS

- SQL
- Microsoft Excel
- Big Query
- Planning

- Tableau
- Google Sheets
- Data Analysis
- Research

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS

MICROSOFT EXCEL - DATA ANALYSIS WITH EXCEL PIVOT TABLES

December 2021, Udemy

GOOGLE DATA ANALYTICS PROFESSIONAL

October 2021, Coursera

PROGRAMMING FOR EVERYBODY (GETTING STARTED WITH PYTHON)

June 2021, University of Michigan (Online)

BS IN ELECTRONICS AND COMMUNICATIONS ENGINEERING

University of the Immaculate Conception, Philippines

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

SUPPORT ENGINEER, CEBU MICROELECTRONICS INC., PHILIPPINES

- Led a team of six to establish a new optical production line from zero output to 100% production mode; promoted to production section head.
- Resolved process abnormalities by collecting, summarizing, cleaning, and analyzing data to identify the root cause of the problem and presented findings to relevant stakeholders.

OTHER EXPERIENCE

2015 - 2020

SR. PERSONNEL PLANNING COORDINATOR, FUGRO SINGAPORE MARINE PTE LTD, SINGAPORE

Supported 150+ offshore survey specialists in the APAC region; skills matched every team project assignment resulting in well-balanced teams, quality, and on-time job completion.

2007 - 2015

DOCUMENT CONTROL SECRETARY, FUGRO SURVEY PTE LTD, SINGAPORE

Edit and proofread technical reports according to company business style.

2004 - 2007

PRODUCTION SECTION HEAD, CEBU MICROELECTRONICS INC., PHILIPPINES

Supervised overall production operations; analyzed manpower loading of a 30-man production team resulting in 100% on-time shipment.